<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CS125 Final Project</string>
    <string name="title_bar">CALM</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="help_text">
         If you feel you might be suicidal, and live in the United States, the Suicide Hotline provides free and confidential support:
    </string>
    <string name="help_text_1">Call 800–273–8255</string>
    <string name="help_text_2">Or visit:</string>
    <string name="help_text_3">http://www.suicidepreventionlifeline.org/</string>
    <string name="help_text_4">For a live chat and additional resources.</string>
    <string name="help_text_5">If it\'s not an emergency, but you want to know more about mental health, the National Alliance on Mental Illness offers information on their website: </string>
    <string name="help_text_6">https://www.nami.org/</string>
    <string name="help_text_7">And a free helpline at:</string>
    <string name="help_text_8">800–950–6264</string>
    <string name="help_text_9">If you do not live in the United States, please seek out local resources.</string>
    <string name="advice_1">Advice</string>
    <string name="break_text_0">Take a break</string>
    <string name="break_text_1">Taking a break from your task can be helpful. If you’re anxious, forcing yourself to work continuously may cloud your thoughts and make you unable to focus. Taking a few minutes to yourself to relax means that you can return to your work with a fresh start that will aid you in keeping your attention on the task.</string>
    <string name="walk_text_0">Go for a walk</string>
    <string name="walk_text_1">If the weather is appropriate, going for a walk outside can be a good way to relax yourself. Fresh air will allow you to clear your head and calm your thoughts, and you’ll be able to continue what you were doing previously in a more focused manner. Try visiting one of the local parks.</string>
    <string name="talk_text_0">Talk to someone</string>
    <string name="talk_text_1">Contact someone you care about and talk with them. Telling someone about your feelings and what’s bothering you can make you feel less stressed or anxious about the idea overall. Take a few minutes to call or message one of your friends or family members to chat with them, and you’ll be able to calm yourself down.
</string>
    <string name="nap_text_0">Take a short nap</string>
    <string name="nap_text_1">If you’re feeling anxious, taking an hour to nap can be beneficial as it can reduce your anxiety. Whether you actually fall asleep or not, laying in bed will naturally calm you down. If you have a pressing task at hand, this method likely isn’t recommended because it may make you more tired overall. Overall, taking a short nap is a good idea as long as you don’t have a task that needs to be finished quickly.</string>

    <string name="breathe">Breathe</string>
    <string name="breath_text_0">Breathing</string>
    <string name="breath_text_1">Take a couple minutes to breathe.</string>
    <string name="breath_text_2">Steady breathing will help calm your nerves and leave you more relaxed.</string>
    <string name="breath_text_3">When breathing, count in fives. Inhale for five seconds, hold your breath for five seconds, exhale for five seconds, hold for five seconds once more, and repeat.</string>
    <string name="breath_text_4">The pattern will calm you and slow your thoughts down, so you’ll be able to return to your task with less anxiety.</string>
    <string name="breath_text_5">Breathe in while the shape below expands and breathe out as it contracts. Focus on your breathing.</string>
    <string name="meditate">Meditate</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_0">Meditation</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_1">Meditation is a good method to calm yourself. A few minutes each day to meditate can help you feel more relaxed as a person overall.</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_2">1.    Sit in a comfortable position. Make sure the position that you choose is one that you’re all right with sitting in for a few minutes as switching positions may interrupt your focus.</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_3">2.    Close your eyes and try to clear your thoughts of any of your worries.</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_4">3.    Focus on your breathing and feel your body move as you breathe.</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_5">4.    Remain focused on your breathing for a few minutes or until you feel calmer. When you feel like you’ve finished meditating, you can open your eyes and go back to what you were doing before.</string>
    <string name="meditate_text_6">\n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n</string>
    <string name="journal">Journal</string>
    <string name="journal_text">Write down your thoughts</string>
    <string name="journal_hint">You can start here.</string>
    <string name="listen">Listen</string>
    <string name="listen_text">Listen to some calming music</string>
    <string name="title_activity_start_splash">startSplash</string>
   </resources>
